

Manuel Yemoh

Senior Front End Developer



+44 7525 00 3188



Manuelyemoh@gmail.com



https://manuelyemoh.com/ http://tinyurl.com/3k9t7h3v

Skills:

JavaScript, ReactJs, NextJs, GatsbyJs, Typescript, ES6, TailwindCSS, CSS2/3, Styles components, Shadcn, v0, MUI, Babel, NPM, AWS, Websockets, Canvas, XML, JSON, Ajax, Jest/Enzyme, SVN, Github, Mamp/Wamp, jQuery/JQM, RequireJs, Twitter API, GSAP, Facebook & Twitter API. Figma, Xd, Photoshop, Premier Pro, After Effects, Illustrator, Spark AR

Media/CRM platforms:

Flash Talking, DoubleClick Studio / DCM, Google ads, Bannerflow, Sizmek, Celtra, Mailchimp, Salesforce, Hubspot, AEM.

Objective

With over 14 years of front-end development experience, specializing in JavaScript frameworks such as React, I've excelled in delivering exceptional results across various projects including high-profile websites, rich media campaigns, HTML emails, and HTML5 banners. Additionally, I've managed a successful design and development production studio for 4 years, overseeing a team of up to 12 individuals and executing campaigns for global clients to meet business objectives. Now actively seeking a new role.

Professional Experience

January 2013 - July 2015, April 2019 - August 2020, September 2022 - February 2024

Bakaman LTD - Senior Front End Developer

During this period, I contributed to projects for a diverse range of clients, including CNBC, Network London, UDUX, Marks & Spencers, L'Oréal, Nucco Brain, Dewynters, Saatchi and Saatchi, Brothers And Sisters, VCCP Media, Maverick Media, and Common Curiosity.

Key Responsibilities and Achievements:

- Developed fluid and responsive web pages using React/Next/Gatsby.js, ES6, and Tailwind CSS, ensuring optimal performance across various devices.
- Built reusable components from front-end libraries, enhancing efficiency and consistency across multiple projects.
- Translated designs and wireframes into high-quality code using programs like Figma, ensuring pixel-perfect UI elements.
- Optimized codebase using React components and sorted data from APIs for seamless integration into web pages.
- Converted static designs into engaging animations using frameworks like Gsap, enhancing user experience.
- Led a team of developers, maintaining high-quality standards and implementing QA/QC processes to ensure project excellence.
- Designed and built responsive HTML5 banners for desktop and mobile platforms, utilizing HTML, CSS/SCSS/SASS, and JavaScript.
- Developed responsive HTML email templates for desktop and mobile, ensuring consistent rendering across email clients.

August 2020 - September 2022

Wellcom London - Lead Developer

Key Responsibilities and Achievements:

- Fully hands on developer while managing a team of Developers and Permalancers to handle production and new technologies for Display advertising.
- Crafting templates and guidelines while keeping up to date with new technologies to ensure the best user experience for our clients.
- Dealing with new project scoping and being the bridge between PM's and my Dev team to allocate the right resource for the right job.
- Assisting the QA team with technical QA such as checking display ads are adhering to guidelines sent by the client.
- Converting legacy code to more manageable fluid code to ensure longevity of dynamic projects.
- Managing a team of developers and allocating resources for projects.
- Key point of contact between management/project management team and the development team.
- Setting goals and objectives and having regular reviews to discuss progression and strengths and weaknesses.
- Involved in meetings about new business and meetings discussing new platforms and technologies we can integrate with our workflow.



Manuel Yemoh

Senior Front end developer



+44 7525 00 3188



Manuelyemoh@gmail.com



https://manuelyemoh.com/ http://tinyurl.com/3k9t7h3v

Skills:

JavaScript, ReactJs, NextJs, GatsbyJs, Typescript, ES6, TailwindCSS, CSS2/3, Styles components, Shadcn, v0, MUI, Babel, NPM, AWS, Websockets, Canvas, XML, JSON, Ajax, Jest/Enzyme, SVN, Github, Mamp/Wamp, jQuery/JQM, RequireJs, Twitter API, GSAP, Facebook & Twitter API. Figma, Xd, Photoshop, Premier Pro, After Effects, Illustrator, Spark AR

Media/CRM platforms:

Flash Talking, DoubleClick Studio / DCM, Google ads, Bannerflow, Sizmek, Celtra, Mailchimp, Salesforce, Hubspot, AEM. July 2015 - March 2019

Gameyfi - Technical Director / Founder Key Responsibilities and Achievements:

- Designing and developing full campaigns to specific briefs in all types and formats
 websites, games, landing pages, competition pages, email campaigns using mailchimp and other email clients.
- Building wordpress websites and creating social media assets.
- Producing dynamic campaigns in DoubleClick.
- Upholding high standards of quality assurance of work.
- Management of project scope and changes using tools such as Gantt charts.
- Working closely with developers on troubleshooting coding issues.
- High level reporting to key stakeholders on project status.

November 2010 - September 2012

Addiction London - Interactive Developer

- Working in a team of developer and designers in a fast paced agency.
- Exploring new techniques to animate HTML5 banners using Gsap.
- Creating interactive games for high profile clients.
- Creating landing pages with a key eye for detail.

Education

September 2006 - June 2009
 Leeds Metropolitan University
 Degree in BCS - Computer games design

Grade: 2-1

Extra Achievements

July 2018 - Present

Festival of code

Involved as a mentor for children aged between 8-16 at the festival of code which runs every year in the summer.

 \bigcirc